Finding aid to the Nancy Toppan Little papers CA.MS.00018
Smith College Archives
Nancy Toppan Little papers
1914-1978
1914-1918
Smith College Archives
Little, Nancy Toppan.
CA.MS.00018
0.417 linear feet (1 container)
Smith graduate. Contains correspondence from Smith, memorabilia book, class songs, programs, and memoirs of college reunions.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown
Biographical / Historical
Nancy Toppan Little, class of 1918, lived her entire life in Newburyport, Massachusetts. During her four years at Smith she studied Math, English, German, History, Latin, Biblical Literature, Geology, Philosophy, Physics, Economics and Physical Education and was a member of the Math Club. She also taught classes in Arithmetic and Geography at the People's Institute of Northampton. Between her graduation and her marriage on June 16, 1920 to Herbert Greenleaf Noyes, also of Newburyport, she worked briefly as a bank clerk. Her sixty-one-year marriage produced three sons, nine grandchildren and many great-grandchildren. Until her death in 1995, Little delighted in outdoor walks and visits from her large family.
Related Material
80. Class of 1918 Records
Scope and Contents
The Nancy Toppan Little Papers contain correspondence to her family from her enrollment at Smith College in 1914 until her graduation in 1918. The papers also contain materials relating to her college career, including a memorabilia book, class songs, programs from Smith theatrical events, and memoirs of her 45th and 60th college reunions.
Little, Nancy Toppan.; Smith College--Students.
- Correspondence, Sept 1914 - Dec 1914 (Box 1916, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, Jan 1915 - June 1915 (Box 1916, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, Sept 1915 - Dec 1915 (Box 1916, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, Jan 1916 - June 1916 (Box 1916, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, Sept 1916 - Dec 1916 (Box 1916, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, Jan 1917 - June 1917 (Box 1916, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, Sept 1917 - Dec 1917 (Box 1916, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, Jan 1918 - June 1918 (Box 1916, Folder 8)
- Memorabilia Book, 1914 - 18 (Box 1916, Folder 9)
- Photographs, 1918; undated (Box 1916, Folder 10)
- Smith College- Athletic Invitations, 1916 - 18 (Box 1916, Folder 11)
- Smith College- Class Songs, 1915; 1918; undated (Box 1916, Folder 12)
- Smith College- Concert Programs, 1915 - 18 (Box 1916, Folder 13)
- Smith College- Miscellaneous, 1918; undated (Box 1916, Folder 14)
- Smith College- Notes to Nancy Little, 1914; 1915; 1916; undated (Box 1916, Folder 15)
- Smith College- People's Institute, 1915-16 (Box 1916, Folder 16)
- Smith College- Play Bills, 1915- 18 (Box 1916, Folder 17)
- Smith College- Report Cards, 1914 -18 (Box 1916, Folder 18)
- Post Smith College- Notes, 1954 (Box 1916, Folder 19)
- Post Smith College- Play Bills, 1919; 1920; undated (Box 1916, Folder 20)
- Post Smith College- Reunion Materials, 1963; 1978 (Box 1916, Folder 21)